India you know I mean we're now the
fourth largest economy in the next few
years we're going to be the third
largest economy probably very close to
inching towards the 5 trillion mark in
the years to come it could be possibly
anywhere between 20 to 30 trillion uh
you know as a GDP when you talk this
kind of growth and this kind of
bullishness uh on the economy standpoint
point. It can only sustain when you have
the entire populace and the multitudes
of the many indas that make India as a
whole get uplifted um in multiple
aspects and CSR therefore plays a very
integral crucial.
Welcome to the section of sustainably
karma. I'm your host Rajiv Tik. Today we
have a very special guest with us Sheila
Kapoor. She heads marketing, corporate
communication and also CSR at ICICI
Lombard. So welcome Sheena to this
episode of sustainably karma. Thank you
Rajie. Pleasure to be here. Would you
like to briefly recap your journey at
ICCI? at ICS Lombard. It's been a little
over three years now that I've been
employed with ICS Lombard and I've been
a marketer pretty much all through um
and wearing the marketing hat and being
a fullervice marketing head um across
the entire on suite. I think one
additional feather to my cap here at uh
Lombard has been adding the CSR uh to
the portfolio um which is again very
close to my heart as well. and you know
one feels uh one is able to do whatever
you play a small but vital role in
giving back to society. So it's um
overall I think it's it's been a great
journey so far. So good. Uh uh we are
India's largest private general
insurance uh player in the country. So
um with health, motor, travel, uh
corporate uh insurance solutions, the
entire suite and bouquet of insurance
services. Uh when you are a market
leader, it puts uh a lot of
responsibility on your shoulders as a
brand custodian to be able to walk the
talk to be able to deliver the trust and
the promise which actually in our
business is inherently implicit and
insurance uh is nothing but an inherent
promise to pay the customers in their
time of need. Um so it's been about the
entire brand building uh making it uh
endearing as well as differentiated
unique um at the same time being
authentic and empathetic. So I think
that has been the cornerstone. Um also
as a market leader one gets a huge
canvas to play at a pan India level
across the entire ecosystem from um
corporate clients, retail audience to
the entire ecosystem of channel partners
and intermediaries that we have. So
we've got something for everybody
practically given the regulators vision
as well ID's vision of insurance for all
by 2047.
uh we take our role and our commitment
to that very seriously in in driving the
penetration and awareness. Um also very
happy to share that uh we've taken
recently the metro rides or the iconic
SDK uh temple. So it's now branded and
called as IC Lombardi Vanak metro
station. We also said that uh CSR is
very close to your heart and you have
been a key player in the space. So what
are the key trends which are shaping the
CSR landscape today? Yes. So um like I
mentioned yes it's very close to my
heart. I think even in my previous
company one worked closely with the
foundation there and one got a lot of
exposure but I think when you talk about
CSR there has been a growth in the
industry one is from a compliance angle
2% of your you know net profits over the
previous three preceding years uh every
corporate is coming forth from a
regulatory compliance perspective has to
indulge and engage in CSR but I think
more more and more corporates are taking
this stance a lot more seriously and um
you know there has been a growth uh
organically about 12 to 15%
um in the overall corpus you're talking
about close to 1.6 six lakh crores um
that's going into CSR programs. A large
part of that is um in the four areas of
education, livelihood, um healthcare and
rural and the other trend um so about
75% actually is centered and
concentrated in these four programs. The
balance is across everything else under
the sun right from whether it is working
in specific areas of senior citizen care
uh domestic abuse or victims, child
abuse victims, whether it is about
vocational training or you know
eforestation
so on and so forth. And I think the
other big trend is that a lot more
corporate especially with the ESJ agenda
and mandate coming into the boardrooms.
Um so that is becoming a mainstay agenda
item and a lot of the CSR programs are
now looking at corporates becoming
responsible citizens and um taking steps
towards building a sustainable greener
uh future and world and planet for the
generation to come. um and are taking
the sustainability aspect a lot more
seriously and taking from small measures
to large measures. But I see that
especially with a lot of global warming,
climatic changes, a lot of the
catastrophe which are now uh happening
and occurring because of natural
calamities and um uh climate related
catastrophes. one is taking heat a lot
more um with a lot of players and
countries and organizations on the
sustainability aspect. So and I think
that is uh going to become more and more
prevalent even in the years and decades
to come. What are the biggest challenges
in in implementing impactful CSR
initiatives? What happens is when when
corporates um I I think it's it's not
it's always with the right intention
rather you know they mean well what
happens is there is a gap in the
implementation
so either one is spread too thin um or
it is so fragmented as a program um or
you know in terms of the designated
areas that the corporates disperse their
CSR budget s into. It is so fragmented
and it is it does not build scale and
long-term impact and it doesn't really
shift the needle on bringing alive that
change from impacting lives uh where you
can see a tangible difference and that
can only happen when you are invested
into it for a long-term perspective and
you move the entire machinery around it
you know and and that If you choose
programs which are synergistic with your
competencies, capabilities, your
business of operations, your
stakeholders, wherever you're able to
leverage a lot more given your corporate
standing and your business standing uh
so as to be able to build long-term
impact and build higher visibility and
bring about a real change. Um what tends
to happen more often than not is that it
it is a compliance tickbox and therefore
one is taking on you know certain CSR
programs which are just about meeting
the compliance needs but it is not
coming with an entire emphasis on
long-term sustainable impact in in a
particular location in a particular
program and where you continue to invest
year and year. the compounding effect
only comes when you're able to invest in
a certain program and build scale into
it. Um the other bit is even from
metric. It's more about volume and value
rather than again looking at metrics
where you're building long-term impact
and scale. The third is that a lot of
the implementation agencies a lot of
times you know um either from a
regulatory or a due diligence standpoint
um the NGO partners and and there are a
lot of them who are doing incredible
great work um but a lot of them um are
not able to implement with the strategic
direction that was intended originally.
The other complication is that from a
geographical standpoint, a lot of the
corporates and a lot of the CSR
investments are centered in urban areas
and in and around places of work where
the office is situated or where the
industry is situated which tends to be
concentrated um on in the urban and
metro uh sections and thereabouts. it
doesn't really penetrate and percolate
down to the parat and to the tier three
tier four towns and villages where you
actually need a lot of the CSR support
from an upliftment of you know the
livelihood and society per se. Would you
have any policy recommendations to
overcome such challenges? Well, from the
the CSR act is a lot uh exhaustive um in
nature, but I think if one were to um
from a policy standpoint build in impact
measures and metrics and bring in a lot
more accountability and transparency
into that where the onus and ownership
is on corporates to demonstrate
long-term sustainable impact. So I think
depending sectorally from a policy
standpoint um while the entire universe
is large if there were policy um
suggestions and recommendations which
nudge certain sectors and corporates in
certain industries towards um
complementing and synergistic areas and
and bring the entire sector and category
together it would bring a lot more uh
impact. So just to give you an example
um say if it were you know retail or the
apparel or the textile industry if the
CSR programs or the budgets were aligned
with bringing alive the artisinals or
the tribals or you know bring a lot more
support from these um intermediaries and
audiences and communities. you would you
would benefit a lot more from a large
scale impact. So, it's it's still
synergistic with your business, but
you're still able to create sustainable
long-term impact with scale. How can
companies on their own maximize their
the impact of their CSR spend? It starts
fundamentally with a few questions that
companies need to ask themselves
um you know and and be very authentic
about it. Starting with what is the
problem that you're trying to solve?
fundamentally right. Um two, you know,
is there an opportunity in that problem
for the company to play an active role?
Three, is it going to be an investment
which is sustainable over long-term? Um
will it be able to create impact over
long-term? Again, have a you know
long-term window and lens uh to the
strategy. Um and and fourth bring in the
right implementing uh partners and
agencies uh on board but also activate
and amplify and leverage the entire
ecosystem of stakeholders whichever
corporate or industry or sector that you
kind of work with. So for instance you
know at at at ICS Lombard we are in the
business of um motor insurance. We are
in the business of health insurance.
Synergistically speaking healthcare
brings a lot of synergies for us from a
business standpoint. Right. Um as the
leading motor insurer player road safety
initiative is something that we've
embarked embarked on and we've been
invested into for over decades now. And
that's fundamentally again synergistic
with the business. Now we are in a
position to leverage the stakeholder
ecosystem. So we're working closely with
the highway authorities. We're working
closely with a foundation like save life
foundation you know which is actually
creating um and uh repairing structural
road flaws in engineering and bringing
about zero fatality or zero accident
corridors in the country. when you work
in the health care and because we work
in tandem and very closely with our
parent ICSF foundation where again you
know as you know ICF foundation is is
doing remarkable stuff in in a host of
areas and and a lot of the uh
initiatives are with an objective of
capacity building um and long-term
sustainable impact. So in healthcare you
know again very pleased and proud to
share that the foundation has committed
um you know 1 1200400 crores to the Tata
memorial um and it's over the next four
years a some of our budgets also get
aligned with the foundation towards a
lot of these programs. What kind of a
role do you see for CSR in our journey
towards a developed India? India, you
know, I mean, we're now the fourth
largest economy. In the next few years,
we're going to be the third largest
economy. We're already very close to
inching towards the 5 trillion mark. And
in the years to come, it could be
possibly anywhere between 20 to 30
trillion uh you know, as a GDP. When you
talk this kind of growth and this kind
of bullishness uh on the economy
standpoint,
it can only sustain when you have the
entire populace and the multitudes of
the many indas that make India as a
whole get uplifted um in multiple
aspects and CSR therefore plays a very
integral crucial role. I think some of
the challenges that I called out earlier
in in terms of making investments which
are with a long-term horizon and with a
very sharp lens on long-term sustainable
uh impact and and a very very clear
metric of what is the tangible
difference that it will make to
individuals or communities lives right
that I think needs to be a lot more
conscious in terms of the corporates
that embark on CSR programs but even
from a lot more coalitions, a lot more
collaboratives, a lot more um multitude
of stakeholders
uh joining hands, partnering um on
synergistic programs and and that is
what will shift the needle in terms of
long-term sustainable impact for India.
Uh otherwise from an income disparity,
wealth disparity, the divide is really
huge. um and it will only get wider um
if if it is not corrected.
Sustainability is the other side of CSR.
Now, how are you embedding
sustainability in your operations? Like
I mentioned, you know, ESG is become a
boardroom agenda and mandate. Um, so
even for us, we have an ESG reporting.
Um, and as a listed company, um, you
know, even from a compliance
perspective, we report on our, uh, ESG
initiatives, um, on the E, on the S and
on the G. Even our CSR programs we are
aligned with the UN SG goals and in the
sustainability space um we are working
in in a host of areas when I talk about
environment you know we've been
implementing solar panels um
installations in a lot of the municipal
schools and we've taken forth uh this
activity in over six to seven uh cities
as of now and we're covering over
thousand plus schools. What it does is
it zeroizes the electricity cost uh for
the schools um and that brings down the
administrative and operational costs in
turn which brings in a lot of the um
cost efficiencies for the school um and
therefore they're able to pay better to
the teachers and are able to have a lot
more um you know from a governance and
operating standpoint a lot more runway
uh because of the zeroized electricity
cost. Um even from the sustainability
um and ESG aspect we from a policy
standpoint we cater to over 50 million
policy holders across the country. We
have uh consciously chosen not to um
roll out and dole out physical policy
issuance uh of copies insurance policies
u simply because you know uh one can go
paperless and green. So you know today
customers and policy holders can receive
their policies on on a WhatsApp on their
mobile on an email um and uh for certain
senior citizens who do need um the
physical copy it is you know as and when
whoever requests it we give it out but
you know that small change itself brings
in a lot more efficiencies um and from a
sustainable aspect we have um installed
a lot more sensor driven in electricity
uh panels and lighting uh options. Um we
are conscious about um even the ensuring
as well as utilizing the EVs from an
ecosystem standpoint so that you're able
to again have a more sustainable
conscious driven initiative. We
encourage our employees to come forward
and share their respective ideas
whatever it is that they are embarking
upon from their own personal as well as
from professional standpoint. A lot of
paper saving options where we've gone
with trying to not print unless and
absolutely you know necessary. um even
travel costs wherever it is possible to
have uh a hybrid working space or work
out of you know um a meeting which is uh
or an office space which is close uh so
that you're again able to efficiently
utilize on the fuel and now we're going
a step forward where we're also looking
at all our suppliers and the
intermediaries and uh exploring what is
you know do they follow the standards
from an ESG G uh perspective and we want
to then collaborate with those players
who meet um the ESG's uh narrative and
imperative. One of your interesting
initiatives is caring hands. Would you
like to give a sense of what it is about
to our audiences for a good CSR program?
Another imperative is how you're able to
activate and leverage different
ecosystem of communities. Uh, Caring
Hands is a very special program because
it's a 100% employee volunteering
initiative um where there is um a deep
sense of pride and gratification
associated with employees coming forward
and uh participating in this. It's it's
an annual program that we've been
running now for again over a decade. Um
but on one singular day we galvanize
over close to 5,000 of our employees
across India who travel across say 50 60
cities and cover about 300 to 400
municipal schools. We create teams with
captains, co- captains and and team
members who scout the municipal school
who you know um and centrally we've
created an entire template that we roll
it out to the to the entire
organization. Um and centrally we we do
out the format and the support but the
team captains are the ones who identify
the municipal school and then coordinate
with the local team from an optimism uh
perspective uh where we do eye checkup
camps for kids. Um you'd be surprised
but 15 to 18% of uh kids children below
the age of 12 13 are actually impacted
by vision problems. And a lot of times
they're overcompensating for it with a
lot of other behaviors because it's not
getting diagnosed and it's not getting
identified early on and that affects
their entire learning and uh you know
educational journey and a lot of times
even the parents are unaware you know
that the kids are suffering from a
vision problem. They just think nadan
balak nutk balak and you know is is
trying to avoid homework or is wanting
to go play but the chances are that you
know he or she is struggling to read or
struggling to um from the blackboard or
notebooks you know and is therefore
really close or is overcompensating for
it saying okay I don't want to do this
because it's taxing a lot but coming
back to caring hands it's a very
beautiful initiative cuz like I said
5,000 of Our employees go out to cover
about 500 you know schools. Um we've
covered lacks of beneficiaries where we
conduct the eye checkup camps along with
the teachers and the principles uh
support and then uh basis whoever needs
uh corrective vision and and spectacles.
We then distribute um the spectacles
back to them in you know and we close
the loop about 2 weeks later. It's very
endearing and it's very gratifying. Uh I
myself have you know gone to the schools
and and everyone across the board our
CEO our mancom you know um to you know
the entire hierarchy across the chain uh
you know a lot of employees come forward
uh you know to participate and it's uh
it's it's great to see and leverage
that. Thanks a lot. It was wonderful
talking to you. Thank you like this
program. We look forward to your
feedback on our WhatsApp number
981812054.
For participation in this program, write
to us at sustainability.
Karma@gmail.com.
Looking forward to meet you again at the
same time next week with a new episode
and a new guest. Till then, goodbye from
all of us.
Sustainability Karma, a podcast series
on sustainable development,
sustainability and ESG.
[Music]